## **BECON DANIEL O.**

Mr., Engr, Developer

10, Umazor close odukoya estate, Akowonjo road, Lagos State. +2348037026969 becondaniel@outlook.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Software Developer, Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. I am Skilled in Communication, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Management, Microsoft Excel, and Engineering. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused on metallurgical/material. engineering from Nnamdi Azikiwe University.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Frontend Developer
- JavaScript
- ReactJS Developer
- Spreadsheets
- Excel
- SQL Server
- PowerBI | Tableau

- Bootstrap | | Tailwind CSS
- SCSS
- Material Engineering
- Performance Management
- Team Building and Leadership
- Complex Problem-solving Abilities
- Interpersonal Communication Skills

**Technical Skills:** Microsoft Office Suite, MS Excel Proficiency, MySQL, PowerBI, Tableau, Node JS, Express JS, React JS, JavaScript, TypeScript Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, HTML, and CSS.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Senatorch LTD, Awka Information Technology Personnel

Feb. 2023 - Till Date

- Using Technology to make life easy.
- Maintaining website and adding features to suit the business.
- Developing an effective and reusable process in carrying out daily tasks.
- Monitoring the company's website performance using established corporate business performance metrics.
- Providing leadership in the development of staff policies, training, and performance measurement.

## **Key Accomplishments**

- Successfully set up and Revamp Senatorch's website with WordPress.
- Successfully set up a central mailing system with the Zoho Platform.
- Training of staff on using the CRM platform. (Zoho CRM and Pipedrive)

# Bonitas Group LTD, Awka Frontend Developer

Jan. 2022- Jan. 2023

- Bringing UI to life.
- Maintaining code base in the development process.
- Developing an effective and reusable code base.
- Monitoring the company's website performance using established corporate business performance metrics.
- Providing leadership in the development of staff policies, training, and performance measurement.

## **Key Accomplishments**

- Successfully set up the frontend design for the GVE project.
- Involvement in the frontend design for the HSE App.
- Finished a course on Coursera for Frontend Development

## Stanel Group PLC, Awka

Customer Associate Mar. 2018–Jan. 2021

- Facilitated positive relationships with customers and clients.
- Monitored the implementation of discharging and offloading of products.
- Optimized the handling of cash and deposit relationships and initiated appropriate strategies to enhance cash positioning.
- Implemented a reliable work process to help customers and colleagues have a good working environment.
- Ensured appropriate financial risk, accounting, and procedures of the company.

## **Key Accomplishments**

• Successfully developed a culture of accountability in managing the business by creating an accountability reputation for the company.

## Arizona Digital LTD, Lagos

Office Assistant Jun. 2012–Nov. 2014

- Performing general office tasks such as filing, phones, and photocopying.
- Managing calendars, scheduling appointments, and coordinating meetings.
- Creating and formatting documents, such as reports and presentations.
- Involved actively in the strategy phase and the eventual kick-off of the product to clients.
- Providing customer service, including responding to inquiries and handling complaints.

### **Key Accomplishments**

- Advanced my Microsoft skills.
- My organizational abilities improved.

## **OTHER EXPERIENCES**

Frontend Lead; Anambra Techies Community
IT personnel; ANSIPPA
Industrial Training (Field Engineer); Swiss Biostat Group, Lagos.

Sales Personnel; Chi Limited Plc, Lagos
Nov2011– April 2011

## **EDUCATION**

BSc. in Metallurgical and Material Engineering, Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka SSCE.; Command Day Secondary School Oshodi, Lagos	2021 2011
CERTIFICATIONS  Coursera; Frontend Development course by Meta  Coursera; Data Analytics: Data, Data Everywhere by Google	2022 2022

### **REFERENCES**